OYETUNDE AWOTUNDE

London, UK

tunde.awotunde1@gmail.com, 07944447710

Result-driven front-end and back-end software developer with 5 years of experience in web and mobile development using React, Node JS, C# & .NET. Critical thinker, excellent at technical writing, testing, problem-solving, troubleshooting, debugging and collaborator who consistently exceeds performance standards. Lover of blockchain technology.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Programming: C#, .NET, Java, NextJS, Solidity, Python, React-Native, React, Angular, Node JS, HTML, CSS,

Database: NoSQL, SQL

Tools: MATLAB. Visual Basic and Visual Studio environment

Application Server: IIS Server

Operating System: Windows, Linux, Android Platform, IOS platform

WORK EXPERIENCE

IPIPELINE

Senior Software Developer

September 2020 to Present

- Manage a team of 10 consisting of developers, analysts and testers across different time zones.
- Participate in design and architectural plans of the project to address long-term business needs
- Analyse user requirements to develop new functionalities such as the claim process and fix bugs.
- Participate in daily code review with my team
- Test the application to ensure all the acceptance criteria for deployment are met.

Software Developer

January 2020 to September 2020

- Coordinated application development for front-end and back-end management services.
- Compiled software manual and requirements for both the users and the team respectively.
- Collaborated both within the team and with other teams to ensure cross-team efforts in application development.
- Facilitated learning and skill growth in less experienced programmers.

Junior Developer

February 2019 to January 2020

- Developed enterprise software applications to support the business processes.
- Developed dashboard for report generation within the application system.
- Maintained an internal bug list on Jira and promptly respond to problems as they arise
- Investigated technical root cause of software outages and proposing permanent fixes

Graduate Developer

September 2018 to February 2019

- Worked in agile development & GIT workflow with Business Analysts, QA Testers and developers
- Provided application support and maintenance for the project by fixing bugs and defects
- Implemented code and script to the required coding standards.
- Worked on web application coding in C#, SQL, .NET & Javascript, HTML, ASP.NET MVC5

Eze Software Group

Software Developer Associate

June 2015 to June 2016

- Customized an application for Hedge fund trading using C# and SQL programming.
- Developed key functionalities in the Portfolio Management Software (PMS) to help keep track of the Hedge funds' portfolio.
- Integrated REST-based to import & export trade into the application system.
- Customized & designed the Dashboard of the application
- Created an API service to migrate all project tasks to JIRA.

Smart Apps Maker

Software Developer

August 2016 to September 2017

- Developed a restaurant ordering app for android and IOS platforms with a Node JS back-end with NoSQL database and an admin control panel built with React and React-Native for both android and IOS platforms.
- Gathered user requirements, design code and test (UAT) for this application using.
- Developed all the functionalities for both front end & back end
- Tracked all the user requirements using Trello.

EDUCATION

September 2018

University Of Essex - MSc in Computational Finance (Merits)

July 2017

University of Essex - BSc in Computer Science (2:1)

June 2013

St Francis Xavier Sixth Form College - A-Levels

Personal Projects

Polygon NFT Music Streaming Platform

- NFT Music Streaming Service on Polygon testnet.
- Developed with solidity smart contracts and React project.
- Upload songs to the blockchain as NFT and stream the songs.
- View site on https://genuine-croissant-3f54ad.netlify.app/
- Code on https://github.com/tundeblockchain/music-nft-project

Polygon NFT Marketplace

- NFT Market places developed using solidity smart contracts with a NextJS front end.
- Create NFT items, buy and sell NFT on the marketplace.
- Deployed on the Polygon Test net.
- View site on https://nft-marketplace-tunde.herokuapp.com/
- Code on https://github.com/tundeblockchain/NFT-marketplace

Smart Mirror

• Created my own smart mirror using a Raspberry PI, two-way mirror and a monitor which has the capabilities to watch youtube videos, display the weather and time

Video On Demand

• Developed a video-on-demand service like Netflix using Node JS for the backend and Angular for the front end. React Native and MongoDB were used for developing android and iOS apps.

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

October 2019

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer (MCS)